<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>General Tech - Category - PandaX</title>
        <link>https://pandax.me/categories/general-tech/</link>
        <description>General Tech - Category - PandaX</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 23:38:46 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pandax.me/categories/general-tech/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Thread Process</title>
    <link>https://pandax.me/thread-process/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 23:38:46 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pandax.me/thread-process/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Thread vs Process What is a Thread, really? Short answer:
Thread is a subset of a process Longer answer:
Thread is an independent set of values for CPU registers Detailed answer:
A thread is an execution context for CPU, which is all the information CPU needs to execute instructions. Essentially: More about thread
Thread components: Program counter: keeps track of which instruc­tion to execute next Stack: which contains the execution history Registers: which hold its current working variables Example: A single thread could be displaying the current tab you’re in, and a different thread could be another tab.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Async Programming</title>
    <link>https://pandax.me/async/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 21:03:35 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pandax.me/async/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Async Porgramming What is async programming? Async programming is about non-blocking execution between functions.
It enables your program to start a potentially long-running task and still be able to be responsive to other events while that task runs,
So we don’t have to wait our time waiting for that long task to be finished
Example Data may take long a long time to submit to/retrieve from a database. With asynchronous programming, the user can move to another screen while the function continues to execute.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Ssr vs Csr</title>
    <link>https://pandax.me/ssr-vs-csr/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 13:45:28 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pandax.me/ssr-vs-csr/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[When user sends a request to a server, different server responses differently depending on the implementations.
Server side rendering Whenever you visit a website, your browser makes a request to the server. Once the request is done processing, your browser gets back the fully rendered HTML and displays it on the screen. If you then decide to visit a different page on the website, your browser will once again make another request for the new information.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How are blogs built</title>
    <link>https://pandax.me/how-are-blogs-built/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 20:43:29 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pandax.me/how-are-blogs-built/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[How are most of the websites/blogs built? Really? Typically, there are two layers of website building:
Pull content from local file system (md files) or third party CMS Render the website The first layer - Content pulling Conventional blog engines hosted on GitHub (Hexo, Hugo, Jekyll) host their &ldquo;content&rdquo; in files stored and managed by Git.
Gatsby and Gridsome, besides supporting file-based content sourcing, also have plugins that enables them to pull &ldquo;content&rdquo; from a third-party CMS, whether it&rsquo;s a self-hosted WordPress or Ghost, or a standalone cloud-based solution like Strapi, DatoCMS, or Contentful.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Enable Spotlight search on Mac</title>
    <link>https://pandax.me/enable-spotlight/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 11:45:57 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pandax.me/enable-spotlight/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Method 1 Navigate to
System Preferences Spotlights Privacy Add your local disk to the list Remove your local disk from the list The above steps will reindex spotlight on the selected disk Method 2 In terminal run:
1 2 sudo mdutil -E / sudo mdutil -a -i on Above commands fixed everything for me]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Add Google Analytics to Hugo Blog</title>
    <link>https://pandax.me/add-google-analytics/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 22:35:38 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pandax.me/add-google-analytics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Google Analytics Register a google analytics account
Get your measurement ID that looks like below
G-6ED0IWOAJK Get gtag js script
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 &lt;!-- Global site tag (gtag.js) - Google Analytics --&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://www.googletagmanager.com/gtag/js?id=G-6ED0IWOAJK&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;script&gt; window.dataLayer = window.dataLayer || []; function gtag(){dataLayer.push(arguments);} gtag(&#39;js&#39;, new Date()); gtag(&#39;config&#39;, &#39;G-6ED0KEHXFZ&#39;); &lt;/script&gt; Hugo blog Find config.toml file, enable google analytics as below 1 2 3 enableGoogleAnalytics = true trackingCodeType = &#34;gtag&#34; trackingID = &#34;G-6ED0IWOAJK&#34; This is my settings above, you may just need]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>What is API</title>
    <link>https://pandax.me/what-is-api/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 18:05:22 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pandax.me/what-is-api/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is API Application Programming Interface: allows two applications to talk to each other
What is REST API REST (Representational State Transfer): A set of functions for developers to perform requests and receive responses using HTTP protocol
Challenges under API testing API Documentation (need endpoint, parameters, resources, data) Access to DB (Validate response by comparing response to DB) Authorization overhead (Handle tokens) Core components of HTTP request HTTP request methods URI Resources and parameters Request header (JSON, XML) Request body (message content) What is Payload Payload/body is secured input data sent to API In JSON What is JSON JavaScript Object Notation Data format represented as String-text Authentication Techniques used in API&rsquo;s Session/Cookie based Authentication Basic Authentication Digest Authentication OAuth Why API testing is suitable for automation testing API testing is:]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Rest API with Express.JS</title>
    <link>https://pandax.me/express-restapi/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 13:37:22 -0600</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pandax.me/express-restapi/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[To include packages/files Include packages: packages are from package.json const express = require('express'); const router = express.Router(); router.get('/', (req, res) =&gt; res.send('Profile route')); const jwt = require('jsonwebtoken'); Inlucde route/file: 1 2 3 4 // db.js module.exports = connectDB; // In server.js const connectDB = require(&#39;./config/db&#39;) connectDB(); File return 1 2 module.exports = connectDB; module.exports = router; Try catch 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 const connectDB = async () =&gt; { try{ await mongoose.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>HTTP</title>
    <link>https://pandax.me/http/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 15:41:20 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pandax.me/http/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[HTTP methods GET: Retrieve data from a server only
HTTP GET won&rsquo;t have payload or request body, just send URL only, it simply retrieves data POST: Add data (create a new object) on the server
PUT: Update an existing object or resource in a server
DELETE: Delete data from a server
Remove is NOT an HTTP verb
HTTP status code cheatsheet 1xx status codes: Informational requests 2xx status codes: Successful requests 3xx status codes: Redirects 4xx status codes: Client errors 5xx status codes: Server errors 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 Code Status Description 200 OK The request is successful 201 Created A new resource was successfuly created 301 Mising parameter 400 Bad request The request is invalid (My problem) 401 Unauthorized Requires authentication 403 Forbidden The client is authenticated but doesn&#39;t have permission to access the requested resource 404 Not Found The requested resource was not found (API&#39;s problem) 405 Method not allowed HTTP request method is not supported (use GET to update) 500 Internal Server error 503 Server unavailable Ref: https://stackoverflow.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>What is SOA</title>
    <link>https://pandax.me/what-is-soa/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 12:48:49 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://pandax.me/what-is-soa/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is SOA Service Oriented Architecture:
Distributed system architecture where all components are designed to be services
eg. Cloud solutions are based on SOA
Key attributes Services over components Interoperability &amp; Cross platform Loose coupling &amp; Distributed Abstraction against complexity SOA Components Services: Pieces of software that are autonomous, self-contained and accessible
Automic services: well-defined and independent Composite: fusion of two or more automic services Types: frontend, integration, business, public enterprise, infrastructure ESB: Enterprise bus (backbone of a SOA system)]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
